A Finding Aid to the Peter Howard Selz papers, 1929-2014, bulk 1950-2005, in the Archives of American Art AAA.selzpete
Archives of American Art
Peter Howard Selz papers
bulk 1950-2005
1929-2014
AAA.selzpete
Archives of American Art
30.1 Linear feet
The papers of art historian and writer Peter Howard Selz (1919-present) measure 30.1 linear feet and date from 1929 to 2014, with the bulk of the materials from 1950 to 2005. Selz was a curator at the Museum of Modern Art in New York and founding director of University Art Museum at the University of California, Berkeley. He also taught at the Chicago Institute of Design, Pomona College, and Berkeley University. The papers document Selz’s career. Found within the papers are correspondence, writings, professional files, project files, membership and association records, artist research files, exhibition files, personal business records, printed materials, and scrapbooks.
The papers of art historian and writer Peter Howard Selz (1919-present) measure 30.1 linear feet and date from 1929 to 2014, with the bulk of the materials from 1950 to 2005. The papers document Selz’s long career via correspondence, writings, professional files, project files, membership and association records, artists’ research files, exhibition files, personal business records, printed materials, and nine scrapbooks.
Selz, Peter Howard, 1919-
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 10 series. When possible the original order of Peter Selz was maintained. However, multiple accessions were merged and integrated.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1942-2013 (2.3 linear feet; Box 1-3)
Series 2: Writings, 1942-2011 (7.8 linear feet; Box 3-10, OV 32)
Series 3: Professional Files, 1949-2012 (1 linear feet; Box 11)
Series 4: Project Files, 1962-2008 (2.6 linear feet; Box 12-14, OV 33)
Series 5: Membership and Association Records, 1958-2013 (0.8 linear feet; Box 14-15)
Series 6: Artists' Research Files, 1955-2014 (7.9 linear feet; Box 15-22, OV 34-35)
Series 7: Exhibition Files, 1960-2012 (5 linear feet; Box 23-27)
Series 8: Personal Business Records, 1929-2011 (1.1 linear feet; Box 28-29, OV 36)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1957-2004 (0.3 linear feet; Box 29)
Series 10: Scrapbooks, 1947-2012 (1.3 linear feet, Box 29-31)
Biographical/Historical note
Peter Howard Selz (1919-) is a pioneering historian of modern art, professor, and writer who taught at the University of California, Berkeley, from 1965-1988 and founded and directed the Berleley Art Museum from 1965-1973.
Selz was born in 1919 in Munich, Germany to Eugene Selz and Edith Drey Selz. In 1936, the family fled Nazi Germany and immigrated to the United States. Selz attended Columbia University from 1937 to 1938 and became a naturalized citizen in 1942. During World War II, Selz served in the U.S. Army in the Office of Strategic Services. He married writer Thalia Cheronis in 1948 but they later divorced in 1965; he married several times afterwards.
After the war, Selz attended and taught at the University of Chicago where he received a Ph. D. in German Expressionism. He spent a year in Paris, 1949-1950, at the Sorbonne and École du Louvre on a Fulbright grant. He received a second Fulbright grant in 1953 to study at the Royal Museums of Art and History in Belgium. From 1953-1955, Selz also taught at the Chicago Institute of Design.
In 1955 Peter Selz accepted a position to chair the art history department at Pomona College in Claremont and relocated to California for a few years. He also became director of the college’s art gallery.
In 1958 Selz moved to New York City to become curator of painting and sculpture at the Museum of Modern Art and was there through the transformative mid-1960s. While at MOMA, he organized several significant exhibitions of modern art, including the 1960 Jean Tinguely "Homage to New York," a sculpture that destroyed itself (and started a fire) in the sculpture garden of the museum; New Images of Man (1959), the Art Nouveau show (1960), and the Art of Assemblage (1961). He also launched important retrospectives, including the first Rodin retrospective in the United States and a comprehensive exhibition of Alberto Giacometti’s work in 1965.
In 1965, Peter Selz returned to California to become the founding director of the Berkeley Art Museum at the University of California, Berkeley, a position he held until 1973. He organized exhibitions of Funk, film, and ceramicists like Peter Voulkos and Robert Arneson. Peter Selz later became project director for Christo’s “Running Fence”, the 24.5-mile long fabric fence over the Marin County hills in 1976. He also served concurrently as a professor of art history at UC until retiring in 1988.
Peter Selz was a member of the College Art Association's board of directors for two terms, 1958-1964 and 1966-1971. Selz is a prolific writer, and the author or co-author of numerous books, exhibition catalogs, and articles. Notable books include German Expressionist Painting (1957), Art in a Turbulent Era (1965), Art in Our Times (1981), and Sam Francis (1975).
In 1988 Peter Selz was named emeritus professor at University of California, Berkeley. In 1993 he was on the acquisitions committee of the Museums of Fine Arts, San Francisco. In 2012, Selz curated The Painted Word exhibition. He lives in California and continues to be active in the art world.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. Research Center. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 2343-2345 and 4383-4385 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the microfilm is incomplete and does not represent the entire collection. The filmed order does not match the current arrangement of the papers as outlined in this finding aid.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Peter Howard Selz papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by Peter Selz in multiple installments from 1976 through 2014.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art also holds oral history interviews of Peter Selz conducted by Paul J. Karlstrom on July 28, 1982, October 12, 1982, and November 3, 1999.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art historian and writer Peter Howard Selz (1919-present) measure 30.1 linear feet and date from 1929 to 2014, with the bulk of the materials from 1950 to 2005. The papers document Selz’s long career via correspondence, writings, professional files, project files, membership and association records, artists’ research files, exhibition files, personal business records, printed materials, and nine scrapbooks.
Correspondence is with colleagues, artists, museums, and galleries concerning a wide variety of topics, including exhibitions and publications. The bulk of the correspondence consists of alphabetical files (two linear feet) that includes correspondence with artists. Notable correspondents include Pol Bury, Alexander Calder, Gordon Onslow Ford, Alberto Giacometti, Morris Graves, Philip Guston, Dimitri Hadzi, Jacques Lipchitz, Georgia O’Keeffe, Ad Reinhardt, Mark Rothko, Jean Tinguely, and others. Eight additional files of chronological correspondence is with curators, arts organizations, and publishers. Additional correspondence is found in the professional files, project files, membership files, artists’ research files, and exhibition files.
The bulk of the writings series is comprised of files related to Selz's books and includes typescript drafts and galleys, printed material, correspondence, and publishing contracts. Files are found for Art in Our Times, Art of Engagement, Beyond the Mainstream, and Theories of Modern Art. Other writings consist of drafts of articles, essays, notes, and lectures by Selz, along with a few writings by others. There is 1 sound disc and 1 floppy disc.
Professional files document curatorial and teaching positions at the Chicago Institute of Design, Pomona College, University of California, Berkeley, and the Museum of Modern Art. The series includes contracts, recommendations, syllabi, and correspondence.
Project files document Selz’s professional work on specific art projects, panels, and symposiums. There is extensive documentation of Selz’s work as project director of Christo’s Running Fence, as well as other environmental art work projects by Christo, the Berkeley Art Project, Disney Art Project, “Funk Art” symposium, and the “Art and Politics in the 20th Century” symposium. Project files contain a wide variety of materials, such as correspondence, printed material, financial records, reports, photographs, and other documents. There are 2 tape reels, 1 VHS, and 1 sound cassette.
Membership and association records document Selz’s involvement with or membership in various art councils, trustee boards, such as the College Art Association, Art in Chicago Advisory Committee, Bay Area Rapid Transit (B.A.R.T.) Art Council, and the San Francisco Crafts and Folk Art Museum Advisory Board, among others. Materials include meeting minutes, bulletins, correspondence, and memoranda.
Artists’ Research Files consist of a wide variety of research materials Selz compiled about artists for lectures, writings, projects, exhibitions, etc. Files vary and may include original and photocopied correspondence, photographic material, resumes, printed material, and writings. There are also 11 CDs and 1 sound cassette. Files are found for Bedri Baykam, Max Beckmann, Fletcher Benton, Ciel Bergman, Barbara Chase-Riboud, Bruce Conner, Jean Dubuffet, Lyonel Feininger, Leon Golub, Dimitri Hadzi, Rico Lebrun, Harold Paris, Irving Petlin, among many others.
Exhibition files include catalogs, reviews, clippings, writings, correspondence, and other material documenting exhibitions organized by Selz. Limited materials are found for the MOMA Art Nouveau exhibition. More extensive documentation is found for Seven Decades of Modern Art, 1895-1965, The Joint Show (1967), The American Presidency in Political Cartoons (1976), American Modern Art Between the Two World Wars (1979), German Realism in the Twenties: Artist As Social Critic (1980), Twelve Artists from the German Democratic Republic (1989), a Richard Lindner Retrospective (1996), Spaces of Nature (1999), Color and Fire: Defining Moments in Studio Ceramics, 1950-2000 (2000), and a Nathan Oliviera Retrospective (2002), among others. There are 4 CDs.
Personal business records are related to the Mark Rothko estate and Kate Rothko’s legal case against Marlborough Gallery, Inc. Also included in this series are Peter Selz’s school transcripts, bequests, royalty statements, house designs, and other material.
Printed materials include clippings, prints of articles written by Peter Selz, and photocopies of artwork images.
There are nine disbound scrapbooks dating from the 1940s up through 2012 containing clippings, exhibition announcements, and photographs of art events, Selz, and artists.
Scope and Contents note
Baykam, Bedri, 1957-; Beckmann, Max, 1884-1950; Benton, Fletcher; Bergman, Ciel, 1938-; Bury, Pol, 1922-2005; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Chase-Riboud, Barbara; Christo, 1935-, Running fence; Christo, 1935-; College Art Association of America.; Conner, Bruce; Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-; Feininger, Lyonel, 1871-1956; Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966; Golub, Leon, 1922-2004; Graves, Morris, 1910-; Guston, Philip, 1913-1980; Hadzi, Dimitri, 1921-2006; Institute of Design (Chicago, Ill.). (Faculty); Lebrun, Rico, 1900-1964; Lindner, Richard, 1901-; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Marlborough Gallery.; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.).; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Onslow-Ford, Gordon; Paris, Harold, 1925-; Petlin, Irving, 1934-; Pomona College. (Claremont, Calif.); Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967; Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970; San Francisco Bay Area Rapid Transit District (Calif.).; Tinguely, Jean, 1925-; University of California, Berkeley. University Art Museum.; Art historians--California--Berkeley; Art, Modern--20th century--Exhibitions; Art--Germany; Art--Political aspects; Art--Study and teaching--California; Authors--California--Berkeley; Ceramics; Environmental art; Painting, Abstract; Photographs; Political cartoons; Pop art--Exhibitions; Realism in art--Germany; San Francisco Bay Area (Calif.); Scrapbooks; Sound recordings; Video recordings
- Correspondence, 1942-2013; Series 1; 2.3 Linear feet Box 1-3
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence with friends, colleagues, artists, museums, and galleries. Additional correspondence is found in writings, professional files, project files, membership and association files, artists' research files, exhibition files, and personal business records.
  Arrangement note
  The bulk of the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of artist, organization, museum, gallery, and an occasional subject. There are eight files of chronological correspondence representing Selz's original filing order.
  This series is further arranged as 2 subseries.
  1.1: Alphabetical Correspondence, 1942-2013
  1.2: Chronological Correspondence, 1970-2012
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1942-2013; 1.1
    This subseries includes correspondence with artists, curators, art dealers, museums, universities, and galleries regarding a variety of topics, including upcoming exhibitions and publications. Notable correspondents include Pol Bury, Alexander Calder, Gordon Onslow Ford, Alberto Giacometti, Morris Graves, Dimitri Hadzi, Jacques Lipchitz, Georgia O’Keeffe, Ad Reinhardt, Mark Rothko, Jean Tinguely, and many others.
    Alphabetical files, for the most part, represent general correspondence arranged by Selz. The correspondence relates to additional correspondence found in other series. Letters from unidentified correspondents, due to illegibility or the absence of a surname, are grouped together in a folder next to the end of the series. The last folder in the subseries consists of photocopies of letters from artists.
    - Adamson, Glenn, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alphonse Berber Gallery, circa 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Andersen, Wayne, 2001-2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Art Journal, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Association Internationale des Critiques d'Art (AICA), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1959-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Baskin, Leonard, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bauhaus Archive, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Baykam, Bedri, 1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Berolzheimer, Michael, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bury, Pol, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - B, Miscellaneous, 1953-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Campoli, Cosmo, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Chase-Riboud, Barbara, 1973-2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - China Trip, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Folder includes correspondence related to a series of lectures at the Shaanxi Association of Artists and the Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts in China.
    - Columbus Museum of Art, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Conner, Bruce, 1960-2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1961-2002 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Demarco, Richard, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - D, Miscellaneous, 1962-2002 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Elsen, Albert, 1963-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Erskine, Peter, circa 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Feng, Gang, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Ford, Gordon Onslow, 1993-2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Fresno Art Museum, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Frye Art Museum, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - F, Miscellaneous, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Geiser, David, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Giacometti, Alberto, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Gilhooly, David, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Goeritz, Mathias, 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Grande, John, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Graves, Morris, 1968-1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Guston, Philip, 1963-1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1954-2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1987-2004 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Heartfield, Gertrud, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Henry Art Gallery, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Henry Moore Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - H, Miscellaneous, 1963-2005 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - International Sculpture Center, 1998-2008 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Joram Harel Management, 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Jouffroy, Alain, circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Jüdisches Museum Berlin, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Kitaj, Ron, 1967-2001 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - K, Miscellaneous, 1955-2001 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Landauer, Susan, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Len Lye Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Liu, Chi, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - L, Miscellaneous, 1962-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Marlborough Gallery, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Moeller, Achim, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Morgan, Robert, 1994-2013 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Musée d'Art Américain, Giverny, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Museum of Contemporary Religious Art, 1992-2010 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1975-2012 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - M, Miscellaneous, 1955-2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - National Galleries of Scotland, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - N, Miscellaneous, 1942-2005 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Oakes, Baile, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Oliviera, Nathan, 1989-2001 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Paolozzi, Eduardo, 1959-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Paris, Harold, circa 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Partenheimer, Jürgen, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Prestel, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - P, Miscellaneous, 1970-2011 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Reinhardt, Ad, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Rickey, George, 1963-1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Robert Gore Rifkind Collection, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Rosen, James, 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - R, Miscellaneous, 1959-2003 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sabarsky, Serge, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Schneemann, Carolee, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Schneider Museum of Art, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Schultze, Bernard, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - S.I.G.N.A.L.E., 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - St. James Press, 1980-1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Stadtarchiv Munchen, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Stein, Laurie, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Stiles, Kristine, 1987-2008 (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
    - S, Miscellaneous, 1970-2001 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Takis, 1966-1983 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Tinguely, Jean, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - T, Miscellaneous, 1959-2004 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - U.S. Army, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - U, Miscellaneous, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Vedova, Emilio, 1975-2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - V, Miscellaneous, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - W, Miscellaneous, 1959-2007 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Yunkers, Adja, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, 1969-2012 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Photocopies of Artist Letters, 1954-1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1970-2012; 1.2
    Eight files of chronological correspondence with museum curators, art organizations, and publishers such as the University of California Press.
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1970-2012 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
- Writings, 1942-2011; Series 2; 7.8 Linear feet Box 3-10, OV 32
  Writings include typescript drafts of books, articles, essays, and lectures by Selz, along with a few writings by others. Also found are publication and research related materials and correspondence. The series includes 1 sound disc and 1 floppy disc.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  2.1: Books, 1942-2007
  2.2: Other Writings, 1963-2011
  - Books, 1942-2007; 2.1
    This series is comprised of typescript drafts, correspondence, publishing contracts, research files, image rights and reproduction requests, financial material, and reader feedback, all related to books written or co-authored by Peter Selz. The titles include Art in a Turbulent Era, Art in Our Times, Art of Engagement, Beyond the Mainstream, Theories and Documents, and Theories of Modern Art. There are also monographs on artists such as Eduardo Chillida, Sam Francis, and William Congdon.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by title. Some books have folder groupings that are arranged by document type. Most of the book drafts are not numbered and are not in a specific order. The exception is Art of Engagement which had the number of the draft which was labeled "Second Draft," "Sixth Draft," etc.
    - Art in a Turbulent Era (Box 3)
      - UMI Research Press Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Royalty Reports, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Art in Our Times (Box 3)
      - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Harry Abrams, Inc. Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - General Correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13-20)
      - Image Rights and Reproductions Requests, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
      - Reader Feedback for Publisher's Examination Copy, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Art in Our Times (Box 4)
      - Introduction, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 1 Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Chapter 1 Images of Artwork, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 2 Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
      - Chapter 2 Images of Artwork, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
      - Chapter 3 Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
      - Chapter 3 Images of Artwork, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 4 Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 4 Images of Artwork, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Chapter 5 Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13-15)
      - Chapter 6 Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
      - Chapter 7 Draft, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Art in Our Times (Box 5)
      - Chapter 7 Images of Artwork, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
      - Chapter 8 Introduction Drafts, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
      - Chapter 8 "Painting" Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Chapter 8 "Sculpture" Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
      - Chapter 8 "Architecture" Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 9 Draft and Images, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9-12)
      - Bibliography, circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Art of Engagement (Box 5)
      - San Jose Museum of Art Correspondence, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - University of California Press Correspondence, 2000-2007 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - General Correspondence, 1999-2005 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Contracts and Agreements, 2002-2005 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Reader Reports, 2002-2005 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Interview with Peter Selz on KPFK 90.7 FM Sound Exchange Program, 2005; Includes 1 sound disc (CD). (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - "Art and Politics in California in the 1960s" Typescript Draft, circa 2003 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Second Typescript Draft, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Third Typescript Draft, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Art of Engagement (Box 6)
      - Sixth Typescript Draft, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
      - Final Typescript Draft, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
    - Beyond the Mainstream (Box 6)
      - Cambridge University Press Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - General Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Invoices, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)